EVA GARCIA MARTIN



Senior Data Scientist

Senior Data Scientist with several years of experience as a ML research engineer and data scientist. On the geeky side, I love reading ML papers, the latest ML algorithms, and hacking python solutions. On the human side, I love interacting, working and communicating with diverse teams and audiences.



073 422 35 55

@ eva.g.596@gmail.com



github.com/egarciamartin

in linkedin.com/in/evagarciamartin/

Work Experience

Ekkono Solutions (Startup), Göteborg, Sweden

Senior Data Scientist Dec 2021 - Present

Increased responsibility leading customer projects and communication, and on mentoring.

Data Scientist Aug 2019 - Dec 2021

- Tech lead: leading research and customer projects with different companies and organizations, while mentoring new staff, interns and customer data science experts.
- ML Research Engineer: algorithmic development (python mainly, also C++), researching and developing efficient neural nets and unsupervised ML algorithms for Ekkono's library.
- · Working with customers from different verticals, analyzing customer data, mapping use-cases to ML solutions and communicating findings and solutions in conferences and customer events.

Blekinge Institute of Technology, Karlskrona, Sweden

Doctoral Student Jan 2015 - Jan 2020

Indra, Madrid, Spain

Business Analyst Mar 2014 - Dec 2014

Data Analytics on large-scale social datasets using SQL, MongoDB, R, and Python

Skills



TensorFlow

Keras

Scikit-learn **SVM** NumPy

R **Pandas** Java

SQL

Random Forest

Education

PhD in Computer Science

2015 - 2020

Blekinge Institute of Technology, Karlskrona, Sweden.

Researched and prototyped computational and memory efficient machine learning algorithms, for data stream mining applications in large-scale datasets (https://scholar.google.com/citations?hl=en&user=9LJwmLkAAAAJ) (java, python, Č)

MSc in Computer Science

2012 - 2013

Blekinge Institute of Technology, Karlskrona, Sweden.

Large-Scale experimentation and statistical analysis on social Twitter data.

BSc in Telecommunications Engineering

2009 - 2013

Languages

Swedish: Conversational

Courses

English: Proficient

Spanish: Proficient

Italian: Fluent

University Rey Juan Carlos, Madrid, Spain.

Organizing and Volunteering Experience

Women in Tech Göteborg - Meela

Tech Advisory Board

May 2021 - Present

This entails advising the startup on, and through, their product development process ultimately improving the quality of their solution and speeding up their time to market.

International Conference on Data Mining (ICDM)

Sponsorship Co-Chair

Present

Green Data Mining Workshop at European Conference on Machine Learning (ECML)

Main Organizer and Coordinator

2018 - 2020

Women in Machine Learning

Volunteer

2017 - 2018

Deep Learning Specialization Google Cloud Computer Architecture